

# RUDIYANTO

DEVOPS ENGINEER • JAKARTA, 10510, INDONESIA • 082117689050

# DETAILS

Jl. cempaka warna no. 13, RT.10/RW.4, cempaka putih timu Jakarta, 10510 Indonesia 082117689050 rudiyanto562@gmail.com

> Date / Place of birth July 17, 1996 Mancang

Nationality 1205061707960003

· LINKS ·

**Linkedin** 

Github

• SKILLS •

**Networking RS** 

Linux

**Cloud Computing** 

Docker

Kubernetes

Git

CI/CD

Jenkins

Ansible

Terraform

**AWS** 

YAML

Vagrant

Krakend API-gateway

Helm

• LANGUAGES •

#### PROFILE

I am a devops engineer who very interested in automation technology, cloud computing, CI / CD, and software development. Very enthusiast about new technologies and highly motivated to always growing up and improve my skills in IT. And experienced with kubernetes, Rancher, jenkins, Linux, and Krakend API-gateway.

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Network Engineer at Lintas Teknologi Indonesia, Jakarta

March 2018 — October 2020

#### XL AXIATA PROJECT:

- Performing Installation and configuration of all juniper router and switch. Integrating and insert new MBH network to existing MPLS network.
- Perform Migration and hourly report after migration.
- Stagging Juniper ACX, M, MX Series Router and EX Series Switch

#### Devops Engineer at PT. Loyalty Program Indonesia, Jakarta

November 2020 — Present

- Set up kubernetes cluster using Rancher kubernetes engine for on premise.
- Daily maintain CI/CD such as create pipeline job on Jenkins.
- Automation using bash script .
- Krakend mapping endpoint for API gateway.
- Deploy front end service using docker compose.
- Monitoring all kubernetes clusters using rancher dashboard.

# EDUCATION

P Diploma 3, Akademi Telkom Jakarta, Jakarta

September 2014 — October 2017

### ■ REFERENCES

Putu Gandi Mitha Wijaya from PT. Master System Indonesia

putu.gandi@mastersystem.co.id · 081339339987

# COURSES

Devops, Sekolah devops

January 2020 — April 2020

Container, Kubernetes, Openshift, Digitalent Kominfo

March 2020 — April 2020

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA), Udemy

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

English

#### Helpdesk at Telkom Indonesia, Jakarta

August 2020 — August 2020

# **★** CERTIFICATIONS

#### Certificate

December 2019 — December 2021

JNCIA-Junos

#### ★ PROJECT EXPERIENCES

#### Sekolah Devops Project

January 2020 — April 2020

1. Project 1 (Deploy on premise infrastructure for web apps)

Deploying an infrastructure server on premises, such as webserver and database server for simple web application. Use vagrant vm and automation with bash script to set up the web application, then store the source code to github.

2. Project 2 ( Deploy cloud base infrastructure)

Migrate base infrastructure of server from on premises to cloud base. Designing a proper topology for the cloud and minimize the budget as it can. In this project I use AWS cloud provider. Implement auto scaling, load balancer, and using S3 bucket for store the data, and RDS for the database so it is possible to mirorring the database.

3. Project 3 (Deploy container base infrastructure)

Create a topology for the container based infrastructure, using docker for container platform, and Kubernetes for the orchestration. Deploying k8s cluster using kops and the kubernetes architecture use 1 master and 2 workers on aws cloud provider, and divides into 2 environments which is production and staging. And use wordpress app to deploy on the server.

4. Big Project (Deploy reliable and seamless infrastructure)

Build 2 environtments production and staging, and all system are container base, Environtment based on AWS cloud and based on infrastructure as a code so it is easily reusable. Using ansible and terraform for automation infrastructure. Source code store on github and using jenkins for CI/CD. Deploy monitoring system using grafana and prometheus, and logging using EFK.

# Korlantas Digital ID sub service by SINAR application, Jakarta

April 2021 — July 2022

- Set up all environtmen such as develop, staging, and production environtmen.
- Set up all kubernetes clusters on environment develop, staging, and porduction.
- Set up CI/CD for all services
- Implement docker compose for front end service
- Deploy krakend API-gateway on kubernetes and mapping krakend configuration.

# **QOIN Crypto, Jakarta**

April 2022 — Present

- Provisioning all environtment for crypto service develop, staging, and Prod.
- Set up Virtual mechine for monolitic apps.
- Set up gitlab CI, implement gitlab runner on host mechine and create gitlab job runner.
- On going process and on research for implement node RPC solana and binance.
- Deploy krakend api-gateway
- Mapping API endpoint using krakend